<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jonathan Yap</title>
    <description>Discovering insights, designing products, hacking prototype, building UI with code.</description>
    <link>http://jonathanyap.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jonathanyap.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 17:59:13 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2016 17:59:13 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emotivu</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/72469462&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;movie-recommendation-based-on-your-status-update&quot;&gt;Movie recommendation based on your status update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emotivu was the result of Startup Weekend in 2012, an ambitious project that bring emotions, tweets, and movies together. Using sentiment analysis and a complex algorithm, Emotivu recommends you movies to watch based on your tweets. This was the initial proof of concept that slowly evolve over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;emotivu_figure--hack&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/emotivu-app-hack.png&quot; alt=&quot;Emotivu responsive app in hackathon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;1st version of Emotivu from Startup Weekend&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a team of 3, my task was to focus on the design, experience and front end. One of my toughest challenge was making the app responsive, as it involves planning for cross browser and cross devices. This was one of my earliest entry into the full front end development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user flow was vital in helping build the algorithm, as it requires a lot of user feedback to help it learn and improve recommendation and accuracy. We went through countless number of iteration to archive the right balance of feedback and usability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;emotivu_figure--wireframe&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/emotivu-wireframe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Emotivu wireframe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Iteration on wireframe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach was designing in low-fi wireframes and getting the flow right, then jump into designing in browser. It was an challenging learning curve to adopt design in code fully within the workflow, but once setlled, it felt awesome to see it come to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;emotivu_figure--menu&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/emotivu-menu.png&quot; alt=&quot;Emotivu menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;CSS animation for the win!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSS animation was big. Big in terms of how well it performed over all browsers and devices. My target was to avoid using javascript to drive all the animation as it drops a huge amount of frame rates on mobile devices. CSS3 performed brilliantly across most devices, with devices that did not support it would simply gracefully degrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;emotivu_figure--app&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/emotivu-app.png&quot; alt=&quot;Emotivu responsive app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Web app responsive across devices&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User feedback was vital in early development and shaping the direction. The team took the mindset of test fast, test often, so we took to the streets to interview people as to inform the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our app is far from finish as we pressed on to work on getting Emotivu closer to how we pictured it. We manage to secure &lt;a href=&quot;http://4pt5.com/emotivu-wins-techpitch-4-5/&quot;&gt;initial interest to funding&lt;/a&gt; but in the end, it was down to personal reasons that Emotivu did not take off. This has always been close to heart and highly regarded as the most intense period of my career growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jonathanyap.com/work/2014/02/05/emotivu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jonathanyap.com/work/2014/02/05/emotivu/</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tronsquare</title>
        <description>&lt;figure class=&quot;tronsquare_figure--intro&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/tronsquare-map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Transquare Map&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;tronsquare_figure--logo&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/tronsquare-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transquare Logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;light-cycle-game-using-location-check-ins&quot;&gt;Light cycle game using location check-ins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what happen when you mash up the light cycle game from Tron and Foursquare. The idea of Tronsquare first came at the Unlock London Hackathon and the following day it won in the category of Most Innovative Application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team then came together to mash out awesomeness and put everything in full swing. Consisting of myself, an iOS developer, an Android developer, a web developer and an end point server side developer, each of us worked on our strength to create a game worthy of the Grid. In an AGILE environment, I lead the UX/UI development in making the game itself worked before polishing the UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our on going efforts in getting the prototype working has took us closer and closer to our vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;tronsquare_figure--logotype&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/tronsquare-logotype.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transquare Logotype&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Crafting the logotype&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the logo itself, I created a logotype that will accompany the app icon, in application where the logo would not work as well on its on. It took some time and micro tweaking to get it to the way it should be without looking out of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;tronsquare_figure--wireframe&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/tronsquare-wireframe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transquare Wireframe&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Walking through the user journey&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early wireframe did helped the team understand and improve the entire user journey. This helped us identify problems early on which helped on iterating features to include in roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have kept the app simple and basic as our first prototype as our focus was to overcome a lot of development and technical challenges. This proved to be a challenge for myself in terms of the visual aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;tronsquare_figure--lights&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/tronsquare-lights.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transquare Lights&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Developing the lighting UI&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the right colour and glow wasn’t easy. It took quite a lot of effort to get the consistency of light across the UI right. It is essential that the colour also add an element of interactivity and feedback to gamers. This was an opportunity to turn something basic to something that shared the similar aesthetic as the vision in the Grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;tronsquare_figure--app&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/tronsquare-app.png&quot; alt=&quot;Transquare App&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tronsquare app&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the final outlook of the app, in all its pixel glory. It was given very high on aesthetic and intriguing concept as a feedback to most people we tested with. As this progress, I’ve learned a lot from working closely with engineers both on-site and remotely. The project did not progress beyond release due to not being able to solve some of the challenges faced in the back end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jonathanyap.com/work/2013/11/21/tronsquare/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jonathanyap.com/work/2013/11/21/tronsquare/</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>O2 Academy App</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy Concept shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bringing-you-closer-to-the-music&quot;&gt;Bringing you closer to the music&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project started out as a simple refresh in design and added functionality for both iOS and Android. It grew into an opportunity to add more value in the O2 music experience. This also helped us rethink the presentation method and a more engaging way to tell a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;o2-academy_figure--old-app&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-old-app.png&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy app older version&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Initial UI refresh&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of this project was to propose an improvement to the previous version and give it a much needed facelift to be inline with the O2 Academy brand. Purely visual design exercise, which later speaking to O2 Academy team, we manage to identify some ideas to innovate and revisit how people feel throughout the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;departure-of-utilitarian-to-building-up-the-entertaintment&quot;&gt;Departure of utilitarian to building up the entertaintment&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-new-concept.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy app new concept&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;New direction, crafted story telling&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its about the journey from the excitement of getting the tickets to anticipation of attending the big day to the eagerness of finding the next gig. Every event is different and every artist is unique, so an adaptive approach to the app was introduced, making it about the experience that matter to people. We took this opportunity to present the idea in a different light, in the experience of the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-new-concept2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy app new concept 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;User journey in play&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We constructed a set that mimics the event cycle and introduced elements that enhance the experience. Through the set, we were able to communicate an engaging story and paint a much clearer picture in an exciting way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-persona.gif&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy persona character&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Persona and his moments&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This really helped the client understand and engage in the idea of focusing on the people and experience. We were able to encourage a lot of healthy discussion through this little guy, putting the perspective of the user at the centre of the attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-bandpack&quot;&gt;Introducing Bandpack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;o2-academy_figure--new-app&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-new-app.png&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy app new app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Brandpack in action&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the focus now on the people, the event and performer manifested itself to be a crucial aspect of the experience. So, we introduce an element called the Band Pack that allow artists to headline their own event. This allow the app to pull in customised content that tailors to the personality of the artist. We also provide a complete view by pulling in relevant information about the performing venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;o2-academy_figure--new-app2&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-new-app2.png&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy app new app 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;UI that is all about building up to the actual experience&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it easy to pull in information and invite friends to join up for a night of excitement. In conclusion, the idea is about bringing you closer to the music through mobile and we have successfully created the right conversation with the client while discovering a unique way to showcase ideas and creating discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/192736497&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Early Prototyping (pw: bandpack )&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw project through to the successful launch of the app on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.o2.co.uk/apps/o2-academy&quot;&gt;iOS, Android&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-sg/store/p/o2-academy/9wzdncrdqtnv_&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; phone with a slight departure in visual but the core idea remains in the heart of the app experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/o2-academy-launched-app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;O2 Academy launched app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jonathanyap.com/work/2013/07/02/o2-academy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jonathanyap.com/work/2013/07/02/o2-academy/</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Panasonic In-Flight Entertainment System</title>
        <description>&lt;figure class=&quot;panasonic_figure--intro&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ex3-intro.png&quot; alt=&quot;Panasonic Ex3 Intro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-the-foundation-for-entertainment-in-the-skies&quot;&gt;Building the foundation for entertainment in the skies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project with Panasonic is a very large scale, long term collaboration which involves a lot of teams across the world. I was involved in building the experience from ground up and helped shape the standards for a complex B2B content management system (CMS) for Panasonic’s new In-Flight Entertainment solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;panasonic_figure--ife&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ex3-ife-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;Panasonic Ex3 IFE designs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Android powered entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This started out with the work for building the UI in the Ex3 in-flight entertainment (IFE) system. With the latest version build on androidn, allowed for touch interaction and wireless internet in the skies. We could pull in a lot of familiar services, especially for those long hours up in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;panasonic_figure--wireframes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ex3-ife-wireframes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Panasonic Ex3 IFE wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Working with details wireframe for a comprehensive experience&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project then grew into providing a second screen experience in extension to the back seat IFE. We drew up multiple mini wireframes sets to help create second screen UX for users with tablet devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;panasonic_figure--sb_logo&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ex3-sb-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Panasonic Ex3 IFE site builder logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Site Builder with version tracking&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the project was to creat an automated process for airline without additional coding, by building a content management system for site portals. I came up with a logo, with an added bonus of allowing version control for the CMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;panasonic_figure--sb&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ex3-sb.png&quot; alt=&quot;Panasonic Ex3 IFE site builder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Building the foundation that manages the entertainment&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the CMS itself, it was a tool that is build with intention of speed and performance in mind. The transition into a lot more code based design (in HTML/CSS) took hold, taking an inspirational play from flat design, which fits the criteria of cross browser performance and implementation. It was about designing a tool to build and not hinder performance with bloated UI. Working with engineers remotely was an interesting challenge, especially when there are more than a 2 timezones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;panasonic_figure--portal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ex3-ife-portal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Panasonic Ex3 IFE portal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Extending the portal capability&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the capability to airlines, the next step was to build a demo portal that served as a foundation for airlines to build upon. I helped define responsive experience on the portal by re-building the front end and the site structure of the entire site based on previous versions. It also sparked a start to creating a useful content matrix document for developers, project managers and QA to references from by taking an object oriented approach in organizing content, feature, and help shape the roadmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, It was a delightful experience to see the IFE in action while on a Singapore Airline flight. Some of the foundation that was done a few years back are now up and fully operational in a lot of these flights, as I hear feedback from people flying with the newer planes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s truly a remarkable feeling to hear and experience how the foundation laid out earlier is empowering airline to provide a better flight experience to the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ife-sia1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Singapore Airline IFE 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ife-sia2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Singapore Airline IFE 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ife-sia3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Singapore Airline IFE 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/panasonic-ife-sia4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Singapore Airline IFE 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jonathanyap.com/work/2013/03/28/panasonic-ife/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jonathanyap.com/work/2013/03/28/panasonic-ife/</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Worldpay</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/worldpay-intro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Worldpay Intro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;checking-out-the-mobile-payment-process&quot;&gt;Checking out the mobile payment process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worldpay’s payment platform is an easy solution for businesses online to allow customers to checkout. When this project came into light, mobile payment was starting to take off. This is about designing the end of a process rather than the start and getting customers over the last stage of a purchase. Working along side a UX designer and the client, we take a look at all the entry and possible scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;worldpay_figure--wireframes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/worldpay-wireframes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Worldpay Wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Preparing for the world of payments: low-fi wireframes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working closely with the client, we identified the scope of devices that the client wish to support, their capabilities and their limitations. From tablet to high end smartphones to low end feature phones, each of their differences had to be documented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in place to design the low end, tablet and no-js fall back options. It an interesting challenge, especially on the low end spectrum as there were more limitations to work around, such as the lack of touch interaction and the lack of native javascript support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;covering-the-full-range-of-devices&quot;&gt;Covering the full range of devices&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;worldpay_figure--devices&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/work/worldpay-devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Worldpay devices&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A world of devices to supprt, a whole lot of considerations&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The designs were kept to a simple form. This provided the foundation for the payment process, yet also allowing businesses with a little more room to re-style it with their own brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we created a payment process that cover a wide range of devices but still share the same user journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://jonathanyap.com/work/2012/05/20/worldpay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jonathanyap.com/work/2012/05/20/worldpay/</guid>
        
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
